CHARLES VERLEYEN



Ph.: +32497201660 | E-mail: charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com | GitHub: Charles1104 | Birth date: 11/04/1988

OBJECTIVE

Google Cloud Engineer seeking to work with a data-oriented company where I will be able to put into practice my mix of soft and hard skills acquired through 10 + years of education and experience in different countries and sectors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google Cloud Lead Customer Engineer

Dec 2017 - Jan 2019

Fourcast (Brussels, Belgium)

Lead a team of two engineers and act as technical lead and project manager on various infrastructure and analytical projects.

• Google Cloud Data Engineer & Data Scientist

Dec 2017 - Jan 2019

Fourcast (Brussels, Belgium)

o extract insights from the data lake of our clients and build customized AI solutions on Google Cloud

Data Scientist – Professional Data Science Bootcamp

Aug 2017 – Nov 2017

Data Science Retreat (Berlin, Germany)

• Strategic Sourcing Manager & BI analyst

Jul 2015 - Feb 2017

CTA Group (Antwerp, Belgium)

o Procurement & Logistics for the chemical consignment contracts of three gold mines in West Africa.

Project Manager

Feb 2015 – Jul 2015

Cimko (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

• Procurement Manager & BI analyst

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

Kempinski Hotel Fleuve Congo (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

• Supplier Quality Engineer

Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

General Electric (San Luis Potosí, Mexico)

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

•	Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer, Google Cloud Professional Architect	2018-2019
	Google Cloud, Professional Developer, Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer,	
	Google Cloud Professional Security Engineer	Mar/May 2018
•	MOOCs in data science – details on www.charlesverleyen.me	Jul 2017 - Dec 2017
•	Bootcamp in Web development – Devleague (Hawaii)	Mar 2017 - Jun 2017
•	Msc in Business engineering - major in Supply Chain Management (cum laude)	Sep 2009 - Jun 2012
	Louvain School of Management, Belgium and National University of Singapore	
•	Bsc in Business Engineering (cum laude)	Sep 2006 - Jun 2009

LANGUAGES AND COMPUTER SKILLS

Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium

- Human Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)
- Data Science skills: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit), TensorFlow, Keras, Google Cloud, Spark
- Front-end and Back-end skills: Javascript (intermediate; knowledge of Angular and React), NodeJS (intermediate), HTML (intermediate), CSS (intermediate). PostgreSQL (proficient) and Sequelize (proficient).
- **Software Skills:** Microsoft office suite (VBA programmer), Microsoft Dynamic Nav 2013 & Jet reports, SAP (modules MM and PP), SAS (Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- APICS CPIM certificate (5 modules achived). Obtained in September 2012.
- Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise (LSM Conseil www.lsmconseil.com) from 2008 until 2010.
- Volunteer in a South African camp provided care to the animals (summer 2004).
- Sports enthusiast with active participation in Tennis and Swimming; Amateur of Horse Riding.
- Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open Water Certificate".